So this is my last day with Takagi-san.
說起來，今天是 我能見到高木同學的最後一天
MOMOMI JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL
（桃見國中）
Takagi-san?
高木同學？
She's not on duty. What's she doing here already?
她那麼早來做什麼？ 她今天又不是值日生
What?
咦？
This is strange. No one's here.
真奇怪，一個人也沒有
No…
不…
She's here.
她在這裡
I can feel it. Takagi-san's presence.
我能感覺到高木同學的存在
She's gotta be hiding somewhere.
她一定是躲在某個地方
Nice try, Takagi-san.
你還真是天真啊，高木同學
Well, guess I'll just go use the toilet.
那麼，我去上個廁所好了
I've learned your ways, Takagi-san.
我已經識破你了，高木同學
I know your tricks.
我很了解你的伎倆
Here!
抓到了！
No way…
怎麼會…
Hiding under the desk and waiting to strike while I clean the chalkboard?
你躲在講桌下面 想等我擦黑板的時候偷襲我？
Well, too bad for you, Takagi-san.
真可惜啊，高木同學
I can see your shoes!
你的鞋子露出來了
Being on class duty is such a pain.
當值日生好麻煩啊
No one will notice if I don't clean the chalkboard…
就算我不擦黑板，也沒人會發現吧
I guess I'll skip it.
那我就不擦了
Gotcha!
抓到了！
What?
什麼？
What? Where is she?
什麼？那她在哪裡？
Where the heck is she?
她跑到哪裡去了？
Did she already move or something?
難道她已經搬走了？
Is this what it will feel like once Takagi-san is gone?
難道高木同學離開以後 就是這種感覺嗎？
Good morning, Nishikata.
早安，西片
Good morning, Takagi-san.
早安，高木同學
Huh? Where were you?
咦？你剛才躲在哪裡？
So easy to surprise, Nishikata!
你好容易吃驚喔，西片！
Oh. The veranda.
噢，原來是陽台
The curtains were wide open.
窗簾明明就開得很大
You should have seen me.
你應該要看到我的
So, you were watching me the whole time?
所以，你剛才一直在偷看我？
I knew you were on class duty today.
我知道你今天是值日生
This was worth waking up early for.
所以我今天早點起床 真是太值得了！
My shoe trap was a great success.
我的鞋子計謀非常成功
-Hey. -Hey, Nishikata.
-我說啊 -我說啊，西片
What?
幹嘛？
When it's just the two of us in this empty classroom,
當這個空曠的教室裡只有我們兩個人
it feels like we're the only two people on earth, don't you think?
感覺就好像在這個世界上 只有我們兩個人，你不覺得嗎？
What?
什麼？
I wish no one else would come.
我希望都不要有其他人來
Honestly.
我說真的
Takagi-san.
高木同學
What is it?
什麼事？
Good morning!
早安！
Someone's excited this morning.
有人一早就很興奮喔
It's the last day of school and spring break starts tomorrow.
今天是學期的最後一天 明天就放春假了
-Of course I'm excited. -You're right.
-我當然很興奮 -說得也是
Yeah.
對
Good morning.
早安
The last day of second year.
今天是二年級的最後一天
Yeah.
對耶
And your last day, Takagi-san.
也是你的最後一天，高木同學
How lonely.
真捨不得
Let's enjoy our time together.
我們好好珍惜剩下的相處時間吧
Okay.
好
Here you are, Takagi-san.
高木同學，這個給你
Wow.
咦？
Did you all make this?
這是你們大家做的嗎？
Yeah.
對
THANK YOU TAKAGI-SAN
（謝謝你，高木同學）
Thank you.
謝謝
Even if you leave this island, we'll always be friends.
就算你離開了這座島 我們也永遠是你的朋友
Yeah.
嗯
-Thank you. -Anytime.
-謝謝 -不客氣
Let's meet again when you come back.
等你回來，我們再見面
Let's!
一言為定！
I've never even been to Tokyo.
我連東京都沒有去過
It's not a vacation, dummy.
笨蛋，她又不是去度假
She's moving.
她是要搬家
Good morning, Takagi-san.
早安，高木同學
Good morning.
早安
I know, but Paris? That sounds too amazing.
我知道，但搬去巴黎也太棒了吧
You write something too.
你也寫一些話給我吧
Okay.
好啊
-Write one for me too. -Okay.
-也寫一些給我 -好
So, you're not coming back to the island?
所以，你再也不會回來這座島了嗎？
I don't know yet.
我還不知道耶
Will you be in Paris forever?
你要永遠住在巴黎了嗎？
I don't know that either.
這我也不知道
Will you go to high school there?
你要去那裡上高中嗎？
The only two people…
在這個世界上
on earth.
只有我們兩個人
What are you thinking about?
你在想什麼？
I wanted to be the first to know.
我想當第一個知道的人
Takagi-san.
高木同學
Excuse me.
打擾了
Okay. This and the documents.
好了，這個，還有文件
Take these to class.
把這些拿去教室
Please excuse me.
失陪了
What's wrong, Nishikata?
西片，你怎麼了？
Why the long face?
為什麼一臉沮喪？
Is it about Takagi-san?
是因為高木的事嗎？
No, it's nothing.
不，沒事
I heard Nakai told you the news.
我聽說是中井告訴你的
You must be thinking, "Why did he know first?"
你心裡一定在想： “為什麼他比我早知道？”
"Why did everyone know before me?"
“為什麼大家都比我早知道？”
I…
我…
I thought we were close friends…
我以為我們是非常要好的朋友…
Nishikata.
西片
Listen.
我說啊
Have you ever been in love?
你有喜歡上一個人過嗎？
-Love? -Yeah.
-喜歡？ -對
I don't really know.
我不太知道
If that's hard for you to tell then…
如果你不是很明白，那麼…
Wanting to see someone.
想要見到某人
Wanting to hear their voice.
想要聽見她的聲音
Enjoying being around them.
跟她在一起很開心
How about that?
這樣想如何？
You must have felt that.
你一定有這些感覺吧
When you put it like that I guess I have.
聽你這麼說，那我想我應該有吧
Nishikata.
西片
It can be difficult to say things to the people that are most important to us.
要對最重要的人講某些事 有時候是很困難的
Maybe you're just that important to her.
也許你對她來說，就是這麼重要
How wonderful to be young and in love.
年輕時的戀愛真好啊
Take it all in.
盡情煩惱吧
All of it.
享受你的煩惱
-Tosaka. -Yes.
-遠坂 -是
-Nakai.
-中井
Big improvement in Math and English.
數學和英文進步很多喔
Thank you.
謝謝老師
-Nakamura. -Yes.
-中村 -是
-Keep going in third year. -I will.
-升上三年級後也要繼續保持
-Nishikata. -Yes.
-西片 -是
Great improvement in PE.
體育進步很多
Good luck.
繼續努力
-Nomura. -Yes.
-野村 -是
You worked hard this semester, Nomura.
你這學期非常努力喔，野村
All right. You're all third years from April.
好了，從四月起 大家就是三年級生了
Today is your last day in this class. Don't forget anything, okay?
今天是你們在這個教室的最後一天 別忘了把東西帶走，好嗎？
Yes, sir.
是
Before we go, let's all take a photo with Takagi-san.
在解散前，我們來和高木同學合照吧
Push the desks back and come forward.
把桌子推到後面，大家來前面集合
Okay.
好
Okay. Here we go.
好了，來囉
THANK YOU SECOND YEAR CLASS THREE!
（2年3班，謝謝你們！）
Hey, Nishikata. You're standing out of the frame.
西片，你沒有在鏡頭裡耶
Not there.
不要站在那裡
Hey.
等一下
Take a seat.
找個位子坐下
Here.
好
Perfect.
太好了
Here we go.
來囉
I'll stand there.
我到時會站在那邊
We'll count from ten.
讓我們從十開始倒數
Ready…
預備
Ten…
十
Nine…
九
Eight…
八
Seven…
七
Six…
六
Five…
五
Four…
四
Three…
三
Two…
二
One…
一
THANK YOU SECOND YEAR CLASS THREE!
（2年3班，謝謝你們！）
Hey.
嘿
Let's walk together.
我們一起走回家吧
What about your bike, Takagi-san?
高木同學，你的腳踏車呢？
Well…
這個嘛…
I left it at home today.
我今天把它放在家裡了
I see.
這樣啊
Nishikata.
西片
Wanna make a side trip?
要不要繞路去一個地方？
I guess.
可以啊
Where to?
要去哪裡？
Here?
這裡？
Yes. Let's climb to the top.
對，我們爬到頂端吧
Is there something up there?
上面有什麼東西嗎？
You'll find out.
等你上去就知道了
I'll find out?
我上去就知道了？
Wait up.
等等我啊
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
It goes on forever.
感覺永遠爬不完
How many stairs are there?
到底有多少階梯啊？
Total of 415.
總共415階
That many?!
這麼多？
Wait for me.
等等我
We made it.
到囉
You okay? Tired?
你還好嗎？很累嗎？
Never been better.
我好得不得了
Hey. Come here.
嘿，過來
I wanted to see this view with you.
在我離開前，我想要 和你一起在這裡看風景
It's beautiful.
景色真美
Hey, did you know?
你知道嗎？
If you come here with your crush, they say that you'll end up together.
聽說如果和喜歡的人來這裡 你們最後就會在一起
What?
什麼？
There are "415" steps, which sounds like "yo-i-koi."
這裡有415個階梯 聽起來就像“好戀情”
"True love."
你覺得呢？
I see.
原來如此
How did you know that?
你是怎麼知道的？
Hm?
嗯？
Came here with someone before?
你有跟其他人來過這裡嗎？
No.
沒有
I heard it from Mano.
我是聽真野說的
She said she came here with Nakai.
她說她跟中井來過這裡
Really?
這樣啊
Wait. What?
等等，什麼？
What does she mean?
她這是什麼意思啊？
Were you thinking about me just now?
你剛才在想我的事嗎？
About you?
想你？
I was not. Why?
沒有，為什麼？
You're the only thing I ever think about.
我倒是老是想著你的事呢
What?
什麼？
-You're blushing! -I am not.
-你臉紅了！ -我沒有
You're just thinking of how you can tease me next.
你只是在想 接下來要怎麼捉弄我而已吧
That's quite the accusation.
你的疑心病還真重啊
But I mean it.
但說真的
I wish I could have teased you more.
我真希望能多捉弄你一點
Hey, Nishikata.
西片，你啊
Would you rather I move and not tease you anymore…
是比較希望我搬走 然後再也不捉弄你
or I stay here and you live a life of teasing?
還是我留在這裡 然後你這輩子都一直被捉弄？
What kind of choices are those?
這是什麼問題啊？
Which one would you choose?
你會選擇哪一種呢？
Well…
這個嘛…
Of course it's the second one.
當然是第二種
The second one?
第二種？
The teasing one.
被捉弄的選項
Is that so?
這樣啊？那我知道了
So, you want me to stay here with you.
你希望我永遠在你身邊
It's better than you going away.
總比你離開好吧
I wouldn't be able to get you back.
這樣我就永遠沒機會反擊了
You want me to stay close to you so you can get me back.
你希望我在你身邊 這樣你才能反擊啊
That's right. One day, I'll get you good.
對，總有一天，我會絕地大反擊
Get me good?
絕地大反擊啊？
I would have loved to see that.
那我還真想體驗看看
You're just making fun of me now.
你現在只是在取笑我而已
I'm not.
我沒有
Here.
給你
What is it?
嗯？那是什麼？
What's wrong, Takagi-san?
怎麼了，高木同學？
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
That face again!
又是這張臉！
Don't cry.
別哭啊
Smile.
笑一個吧
I want you to keep smiling.
我希望你永遠保持微笑
I want you to be happy.
我希望你開心
I can't tease you if you're not in a good mood.
要是你心情不好，我就不能捉弄你了
Always about the teasing.
反正都是為了捉弄我嘛
This is hard.
這很難
For me too.
對我來說也是
Not being able to tease you anymore.
再也不能捉弄你這件事
It stinks.
真是糟透了
Takagi-san.
高木同學
Let's come here again sometime.
我們改天再來這裡一次吧
Yeah.
好